

Tiago Carreira DevOps Engineer tiago.carreira.pw

Lisbon, Portugal

+351 916 848 806

tiago.g.carreira@gmail.com

inkedin.com/in/tcarreira

github.com/tcarreira

Soft Skills

- Productivity passionate
- Fast learner
- Highly adaptable
- Proactive and autonomous
- Good communicator
- Friendly and team player

Technical Skills









Cloud

Containers



















Technological Values









Everything as code

Community

Personal Interests







Podcasts. Audiobooks

Activeness, Achievement

Learning, Improving

Languages

Portuguese



English



Spanish



French

0000

Having 10+ years of experience with DevOps, I'm experienced with modern technologies (eq: Docker), proficient with Linux systems and many DevOps tools (Kubernetes, CI/CD, IaC) and I'm a Python and Go developer.

Passionate about Linux, Open Source and productivity (I love scripting and automation). No person should be a single point of failure - procedures should be documented and/or automated.

I'm looking towards working with **smart people**, with whom I could learn and help learning; where **autonomy** is a valuable asset and improving is more important than finding who made a mistake.

President of the board of ANSOL - Portuguese Association for Open Source Software (2024+)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior DevOps Engineer @ Montblu / Independent Worker

September 2024 - present full remote | Lisbon, Portugal

Cloud management (AWS) & DevOps best practices with simple infrastructure-as-code (Terraform)

Senior DevOps Engineer @ RedCloud

August 2023 - August 2024 (1 year) Pfull remote | Lisbon, Portugal

- Cloud management (AWS) & DevOps best practices and *-as-code (Terraform, Ansible, Concourse-CI)
- Developing & maintaining terraform providers + internal tooling (Bash, Go, Python)

DevOps / Cloud Specialist @ Globo.com

August 2020 - July 2023 (3 years) PRio de Janeiro, Brazil

- Maintaining an Open Source PaaS (Platform as a Service) in Go tsuru.io | github.com/tsuru
- Managing multiple Kubernetes Clusters (with custom resources) @ GCP 300+ nodes | 15k+ pods
- Core developer on Open Source Software (backend, cli, Terraform providers mainly Go)

DevOps/Operations Engineer @ SAPO (BOLD by devoteam)

July 2017 - December 2019 (2 years 6 months) PLisbon, Portugal

- Data Center migration: bare metal, VM's, networking, data and storage (ensuring no downtime)
- Maintaining 500+ servers (using Puppet), 100+ services, both legacy and modern systems, on-call 24/7

EDUCATION

Certifications

- August 2022 CKA: Certified Kubernetes Administrator @ The Linux Foundation
- September 2021 GCP: Associate Cloud Engineer @ Google Cloud Certified

Training & Courses

- June 2022 CKA: Certified Kubernetes Administrator @ A Cloud Guru
- July 2021 Cloud Engineer @ Pluralsight
- May 2020 NDG Linux I/II course @ Cisco Networking Academy
- Jan 2019 LPI DevOps Tools Engineer @ Linux Academy

MSc. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Técnico Lisboa - University of Lisbon | 2007 - 2013 📍 Lisbon, Portugal

- Major / Minor: Robotics & Control Systems / Computers
- Principal subjects: Database management, Objects Oriented Programming, Robotics

OTHER TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE & PROJECTS

2024 - President @ ANSOL.org (Open Source Portuguese Association) - 2024-present

2023 - New Terraform Provider: Env - github.com/tcarreira/terraform-provider-env Hashicorp Terraform Providers (Speaker) - github.com/tcarreira/terraform-provider-apiserver

2022 - Advent Of Code 2022 - 25 days live solving tech riddles with Go - github.com/tcarreira/aoc2022 Speaker @ Python Brasil (tsuru) - youtu.be/gyLS37NVQHw

2021 - TreeTree2: computer architecture I - github.com/tcarreira/nand2tetris-autograder

2020 - Podcasting (host, audio editor, web developer, designer) - github.com/marmita-de-redon Dashboard website project using Golang - github.com/tcarreira/roaw2020

2019 - Speaker @ Meetups and Conferences (Docker, Python, Terraform...) - tcarreira.github.io/presentations Volunteer (technical) @ Ubucon Europe 2019 - github.com/ubuconeurope

PERSONAL ENDEAVORS

Sports: running (marathon), cycling (Lisbon-Santiago 600+ Km), obstacle course racing, rock climbing Music: clarinet, transverse flute, guitar, piano

Music groups: company's band, TUIST.tecnico.ulisboa.pt, multiple choirs, philharmonic orchestra Video production: youtube.carreira.pw, youtu.be/IKvtB-vNOek

Podcasting: marmita.pt (github.com/Marmita-de-Redon)

Personal skills: therapeutic massage (advanced integrated therapeutic massage course)

Maker: Arduino, Raspberry Pi